<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Globals on www.mirkosertic.de</title>
    <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Globals on www.mirkosertic.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mirko Sertic</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools &amp; Goodies</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/toolsgoodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/toolsgoodies/</guid>
      <description>Technical stuff Cypress
 The web has evolved. Finally, testing has too. Fast, easy and reliable testing for anything that runs in a browser.
 Insomnia
 Design and debug APIs like a human, not a robot.
 Camunda BPMN / DMN
 The Camunda Workflow Engine is the right choice for both (micro-)service orchestration and human task management.
 Lime
 Lime: Explaining the predictions of any machine learning classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal list of interesting books</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/interestingbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/interestingbooks/</guid>
      <description>General software engineering &amp;amp; project management   The Mythical Man-Month. Essays on Software Engineering. Frederick P. Brooks
  Requirements-Engineering und -Management: Professionelle, iterative Anforderungsanalyse für die Praxis. Chris Rupp und die SOPHISTEN
  The Deadline: A Novel About Project Management. Tom DeMarco
  The Goal: A Process of Ongoing Improvement. Eliyahu M. Goldratt, Jeff Cox
  Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams. Tom DeMarco
  97 Things Every Programmer Should Know</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite postings</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/favorites/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of my favorite and evergreen postings so far:
   WebAssembly with vue.js
  Alice, Bob, Carol and Dave OpenCL Edition
  Object-Oriented WebAssembly
  Bytecoder : A Low Level Bytecode to JavaScript Transpiler
  A Domain-driven Design Example
  Improve Test Quality with Mutation Testing
  A JavaFX based Game Authoring System
  Why I switched to static HTML generators</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG
 Mirko Sertic Josefine-Mauser-Strasse 66 48157 Münster
 Kontakt
 Telefon: 01575-1337193 E-Mail: mirko@mirkosertic.de
 Haftungsausschluss Haftung für Inhalte Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt. Für die Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte können wir jedoch keine Gewähr übernehmen. Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
