<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Globals on www.mirkosertic.de</title>
    <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Globals on www.mirkosertic.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mirko Sertic</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 14:10:58 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools &amp; Goodies</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/toolsgoodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/toolsgoodies/</guid>
      <description>Technical stuff JSON Crack&#xA;Visualize, analyze, and manipulate data with ease, a versatile and powerful tool for data representation and exploration.&#xA;Desmos&#xA;Desmos is an advanced graphing calculator implemented as a web application and a mobile application written in TypeScript and JavaScript.&#xA;Architecture Antipatterns&#xA;Discover common architecture antipatterns, learn how to avoid them and overcome design pitfalls! Gain valuable insights, practical advice, and real-world examples to build better software architectures and improve existing ones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My personal list of interesting books</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/interestingbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/interestingbooks/</guid>
      <description>General software engineering &amp;amp; project management The Mythical Man-Month. Essays on Software Engineering. Frederick P. Brooks&#xA;Requirements-Engineering und -Management: Professionelle, iterative Anforderungsanalyse für die Praxis. Chris Rupp und die SOPHISTEN&#xA;The Deadline: A Novel About Project Management. Tom DeMarco&#xA;The Goal: A Process of Ongoing Improvement. Eliyahu M. Goldratt, Jeff Cox&#xA;Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams. Tom DeMarco&#xA;97 Things Every Programmer Should Know&#xA;Knigge für Softwarearchitekten. Peter Hruschka</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My favorite postings</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/favorites/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of my favorite and evergreen postings so far:&#xA;WebAssembly with vue.js&#xA;Alice, Bob, Carol and Dave OpenCL Edition&#xA;Object-Oriented WebAssembly&#xA;Bytecoder : A Low Level Bytecode to JavaScript Transpiler&#xA;A Domain-driven Design Example&#xA;Improve Test Quality with Mutation Testing&#xA;A JavaFX based Game Authoring System&#xA;Why I switched to static HTML generators&#xA;A JavaFX based Desktop Search Engine&#xA;GWT vs. Dragome vs. TeaVM for Game Programming</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/global/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG&#xA;Mirko Sertic Josefine-Mauser-Straße 66 48157 Münster&#xA;Kontakt&#xA;Telefon: 01575-1337193 E-Mail: mirko@mirkosertic.de&#xA;Haftungsausschluss Haftung für Inhalte Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt. Für die Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte können wir jedoch keine Gewähr übernehmen. Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
