<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CMS on www.mirkosertic.de</title>
    <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/tags/cms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CMS on www.mirkosertic.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mirko Sertic</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 08:57:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mirkosertic.de/tags/cms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge Your Hugo Blog with Claude: Automated Content Enhancement using Anthropic&#39;s API</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/blog/2024/11/enhance-blog-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/blog/2024/11/enhance-blog-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;_introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a technical blog requires constant attention to quality, readability, and SEO optimization. While creating fresh content is important, enhancing existing posts can be equally valuable. This guide explores how to&#xA;leverage Anthropic’s Claude API to automatically improve your Hugo blog posts while preserving their core message and authenticity. In fact, this blog was target of such an optimization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;_the_power_of_ai_enhanced_content&#34;&gt;The Power of AI-Enhanced Content&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditional content updates are time-consuming and often overlooked. By automating the enhancement process with Claude, you can systematically improve your entire blog archive without manual rewrites. The AI assists in refining&#xA;titles for better click-through rates, crafting compelling descriptions, and generating comprehensive abstracts that accurately represent your content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CMS to Static: A Journey to Blazing Fast Blogging</title>
      <link>https://www.mirkosertic.de/blog/2017/01/why-i-switched-to-static-html-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 01:43:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mirkosertic.de/blog/2017/01/why-i-switched-to-static-html-generators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;_the_beginning&#34;&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Blog started its life a few years ago. At the beginning, I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dokuwiki.org&#34;&gt;DokuWiki&lt;/a&gt; for writing&#xA;and editing. This was good, but I was very limited by the provided editors and markup. So I came to the point that I needed&#xA;something else. And you will of course ask &amp;#34;what else&amp;#34;? Well, for a Blog, there is a very popular answer: Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I installed Wordpress on my web host, and migrated the whole content. The migration task was easy. But I spent a lot of&#xA;time with decisions like &amp;#34;Which theme? Which plugin? What about SEO? I really spent too much time on this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
